Saravanan Kalimuthu

Software Engineer

sathishdaywalker@outlook.com

+91 979-087-0737

https://sarvarunajvm.github.io/

https://github.com/sarvarunajvm

https://www.linkedin.com/in/saravanan-kalimuthu-01a0a9113/

Summary

Around and almost 5 years of experience in java development & used various technologies to develop API's and solutions. Having a great debugging skills and a fast learner who is proeficient in different frameworks and other languages

Relevant Experience

Software Engineer @Assetpulse, Inc

Oct 2019 - Present

Hands-on experience in Spring-Web, Spring-JPA, Rest-Api's, WebSockets, Gradle, NPM.Involved in re-architecture of the existing product. Test Driven Development able to cover up to 96% of the lines. Having a deep understanding and the importance of code quality, continuously using the SonarQube to reduce cognitive complexity and code smell. Used various design patterns such as Adapter, Command and Builder.

Software Developer @Wellspring Software Labs

Proficiently implemented Design patterns, data structures, and algorithms. Involved in design and development for validating/save master data. Involved in writing tests to log metrics for performance improvements. Wrote and delivered code on time with 92% of efficiency. Worked in China(Shenzhen) for 2 months and provided deployment support.

Software Engineer @CoreNett Technologies

Jun 2016 - Dec 2017

Involved in the design and implementation using Java, J2EE 1.4[Servlets, JSP, EJB, DAO, Action] JavaScript1.2, HTML, CSS.Implement the change requests, along with the application development. Individually worked on Operations Module. It's used for ASM, TSO, Distributor, Retailer, Transaction, and Registration. Also individually worked on the Reports and Map module too. It Contains reports on every master programs. Involved in Unit testing.

Projects

DryUtils in Java

https://github.com/sarvarunajvm/DRY_utils

Collected and solved the common utilities which we face while coding this library will help the developer to avoid the code smells and repetative codes. This library was inspired based on the "Apache Commons IO". This library contains String, Number, Date, Set,List,BLOB & Zip.

PortForwarding in NodeJS

https://github.com/sarvarunajvm/Portforwarding

A Simple tool that will help you to do the portforwarding and reverse proxieing based on the settings.json. This tools is specifically designed to solve the problem to override the organisation restrictions.

Jenkins on Cloud in procFile

https://github.com/sarvarunajvm/jenkins-cloud

This is a simple project to deploy the jenkins application in cloud.

URL: https://jenkss.herokuapp.com/

vue-embed-gist in JavaScript

https://github.com/sudhanshu-15/vue-embed-gist/pull/13

Contibuted to an open source VueJs plugin to embed GitHub Gist in VueJs applications on NPM, with average 270 downloads/week. Implemented continuous integration and deployment on Github workflows. Npm: http://goo.gl/Hjkx2j

Tools and technologies.

Coding Languages:

Java8, Javascript, HTML/CSS,

JSON, XML, Python.

Frameworks/Systems:

Spring, Vue, Vuetify, Hibernate, Junit, NodeJS.

Build Tools:

Gradle, NPM, Maven.

Source Control Systems:

Git, GitHub, GitLab.

Databases:

Oracle, Postgres, Mysql, H2, SqLite.

IDE's and Operating Systems:

Eclipse, IntelliJ, VSCode,

Windows/Linux.

Education

MCA @University of Madras 2016 - 2019

Graduated with 6.48 CGPA. Designed and developed a cloud-based service that allows users to authenticate and make their data secure in the cloud using double encryption with the safe key.

BCA @Gurunanak College 2011 - 2014

Graduated with 6.24 CGPA. Member of the National Honor Society. Designed and developed a webpage for internal exams.

Interests

Technology, Swimming, Music, Video Games, Open source projects, Automation.

Skills and Abilities

Problem solving, Application design, Usability principles, Automation, Design Patterns, Vulnerability analysis, Team player, Quick learner.